## **Anshuman Sharma**

### Senior software engineer

Forward-thinking Software Engineer with an experience of **5 years and 6 months** and a background working productively in dynamic environments. Fluent in **Javascript related frameworks** and **Web technologies** used to develop software within internet industry. Proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy. Easily communicates complex technical requirements to non-technical stakeholders

⊠ anshuman1307@yahoo.co.in	+91 9108880148	Pengaluru, India	<b>in</b> linkedin.com/in/ans	human-sharma01
PRIMARY SKILLS				
Javascript React.Js Next.Js	JQuery HTML5	CSS3 Redux	Git/Github NPM Sr	nowplow analytics
Complex problem solving Soluti	ons Recommendations			

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Software Engineer

Bigbasket.com

05/2021 - Present

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked closely with other business analysts, development teams and infrastructure specialists to deliver high availability solutions for mission-critical applications
- Developed and maintained advanced and high performance web apps used by around a million of end users using React and Next.js
- Created APIs in Node/Express to power the frontend
- Adjusted design parameters to boost performance and incorporate new features
- Implemented snowplow analytics to track and analyze user behavior
- Reviewed code and worked with development teams to correct problems, run test scenarios and prepare for deployment

## Senior Software Engineer

Just Dial Ltd

02/2020 - 05/2021

GENIO LITE - Module for marketing executives, where they solicits prospective customers to buy products and services

Responsibilities

- Development and maintenance genio lite web app using Javascript with React, PHP, MySQL
- Utilized expertise to develop products throughout the software lifecycle, from ideation to deployment
- Converting mockups to functional HTML, Javascript
- Event driven click tracker to analyze user behavior on web pages
- Integrating 3rd party api efficiently to provide excellent page rendering
- Following Scrum process to focus on delivering the business value in the shortest time

## Senior Software Engineer

**Just Dial Ltd** 

06/2016 - 01/2019

Flight and Hotel booking module

Responsibilities

- Development and maintenance genio lite web app using Javascript with React, Redux Node.js
- · Utilized expertise to develop products throughout the software lifecycle, from ideation to deployment
- Creating JSON request and reading response through PHP and Node.js to interact with APIs
- Converting mockups to functional HTML, Javascript
- Understanding and involvement in every stage of Agile SDLC
- Managing releases & Hotfixes for development cycles

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Assistant Systems Engineer**

## **Tata Consultancy Services**

11/2014 - 09/2015 American Express

Responsibilities

- Widgetizing web components which are used by several teams across Amex
- · Utilized expertise to develop products throughout the software lifecycle, from ideation to deployment
- Performing code reviews for adapting to best practices and standards
- Developed the User Interface using HTML 5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery and AJAX
- Communication and Co-ordination among technical teams, and other stakeholders

## **EDUCATION**

# **BTECH in Computer Science and Engg.** SRM Unviersity

07/2010 - 05/2014

## **LANGUAGES**

Hindi English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

## **INTERESTS**

Video Games | Football | Cricket | Watching snakes and wildlife